https://www.weuvcare.com/privacy-policy/

EMEA Sales Representatives
search:
Please select the privacy notice you require from the list below
Privacy PolicyVisitor Privacy NoticeSupplier Privacy NoticeSubsidiary Privacy NoticeEmployee Privacy NoticeCustomer Privacy NoticeRecruitment Privacy Notice
Privacy Policy
Who we are
The pages on the website (‘the Website’) are published by Dotsquares
Limited, a company registered in Registered in England & Wales with
company registration number 4381390, whose registered address is at
Fifth Floor Intergen House, 65-67 Western Road, Hove, East Sussex, BN3
2JQ, on behalf of Hanovia Ltd, a company registered in England and Wales
with company registration number 1473077, whose registered address is
at Hanovia Ltd, 780-781 Buckingham Avenue, Slough, Berkshire SL1 4LA
(‘Hanovia’).
We respect your right to privacy and will process personal
information you provide only in accordance with the General Data
Protection Regulation 2018, the Privacy and Electronic Communications
(EC Directive) Regulations 2003 and other applicable privacy laws.
The information collected and how it is used
We will not collect any information about individuals, except where it is specifically and knowingly provided by them.
When you visit our Website, we collect some basic information such as
your browser type, IP address, internet service provider’s domain name,
which pages you accessed on the site, and when. Details of cookies that
we use on the Website can be found on the Cookie notice.
We use this information to provide you with and maintain the quality
of the Website and to analyse the use of the Website in order to help
guide improvements. Personally identifiable information is not
automatically collected.
If you register with this website for information, you will need to provide your name and email address.
This data is held on our central CRM system and is backed up on
internal IT server, hosted in the UK. Email campaigns are managed
through a third-party vendor ‘MailChimp’ using our Office 365 system.
All IT servers have the SSL certifications in place and meet the GDPR
and International community specification for holding data and are
audited on a regularly basis to maintain the highest level of security.
The information will not be used for any other purpose; it will be
stored securely and will not be shared with third parties. By
registering you consent to this use of your name and email address. In
the event of a breech on our systems, all contacts will be notified by
our IT department. If you have any concerns or would like to get further
clarification on our data hold and use policy, please contact us on gdpr@hanovia.com
Third-party use of information
We will not disclose, sell or rent your personal information to any third party except when a required to do so by applicable law, by government body or law enforcement agency. If you do consent but later change your mind, you may contact us to ask for any such activity to stop.
Internal transfers
We may transfer the personal information that is collected from you to third-party data processors located in countries that are outside of the European Economic Area in connection with the above purposes. Please be aware that countries which are outside the European Economic Area may not offer the same level of data protection as the United Kingdom, although the collection, storage and use of your personal data will continue to be governed by this privacy policy.
Security
Whilst we take appropriate technical and organisational measures to safeguard the personal information that you provide, no transmission over the Internet can ever be guaranteed secure. Consequently, please note that the security of any personal information that you transfer over the Internet to us cannot be guaranteed.
Your rights
You have the following rights:
the right to be provided with copies of personal information that we hold about you at any time, subject to a fee specified by law;the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal information held about you free of charge; andthe right to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you.
If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please write to the Data Protection Officer at Hanovia (as appropriate) at the addresses specified above.
Third-party sites
The Website may contain links to other websites operated by third parties. Please note that this privacy policy applies only to the personal information that Hanovia collect through the Website and we cannot be responsible for personal information that third parties may collect, store and use through their website. You should always read the privacy policy of each website you visit carefully.
back to top
Visitor Privacy Statement
Our name/contact details are Hanovia Ltd, 780 Buckingham Avenue, Slough, SL1 4LA
Please contact us on 01753 515300 or email gdpr@hanovia.com if you have any questions relating to this privacy policy.
What data do we collect?
We may collect the following information:
Your name, company and car registration details in our visitors book;Your name and email to log onto our wireless internetYour image on our CCTV coverage of the siteAdditional personal information in the event of an incident that we are required to record in our accident book or other Health & Safety documentation.
How do we use your data?
To protect or as part of an investigation into attempts to gain unauthorised access or damage to our propertyWhere we have a legal right or duty to use or disclose your information (for example in relation to an investigation by a public authority or in a legal dispute).
International Transfers
Sometimes it is necessary for us to share your data outside of the European Economic Area. If this happens, we will ensure that the transfer will be compliant with data protection law and all personal data will be secure.
How long will we keep your data for?
We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy. Different retention periods apply for different types of data, however the longest we will normally hold any personal data is 6 years.
How do we protect your data?
We are committed to keeping your personal data safe and secure. Our security measures include:
Encryption of electronic data.Security controls which protect our IT infrastructure from external attacks and unauthorised access. Internal policies limiting access to the data.Internal policies setting out our data security approach and training for employees.
What are your rights?
You have the following rights:
the right to ask for a copy of personal data that we hold about you (the right of access);no longer have any legal reason to retain it (the right of erasure);the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data that we hold about you (the right of rectification);the right to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you and to object to us using/holding your personal data if we have no legitimate reasons to do so (the right to object);the right (in certain circumstances) to ask us to ‘restrict processing of data’; which means we would need to secure and retain the data for your benefit but not otherwise use it (the right to restrict processing); andthe right (in certain circumstances) to ask us to supply you with some of the personal data we hold about you in a structured machine-readable format and/or to provide a copy of the data in such a format to another organisation (the right to data portability)
If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, you can email us at gdpr@hanovia.com or write to: The Data Protection Officer, Hanovia Ltd, 780 Buckingham Avenue, Slough, SL1 4LA.
Legal Basis for processing personal data
We collect and use your personal data because it is necessary for:
the pursuit of our legitimate interests (as set out below) ;orcomplying with our legal obligations
Our legitimate interests
The normal legal basis for processing your data, is that it is
necessary for the legitimate interests of the Company, including: –
protecting customers, suppliers, employees and other individuals and maintaining their safety, health and welfarecomplying with our legal and regulatory obligationshandling customer and supplier contacts, queries, complaints or disputes
Updating our privacy policy
We will update this privacy policy as required, indicating the date of change. This policy was last updated on July 23rd, 2018.
back to top
Supplier Privacy Statement
Our name/contact details are Hanovia Ltd, 780 Buckingham Avenue, Slough SL1 4LA.
Please contact us on 01753 515300 or email gdpr@hanovia.com if you have any questions relating to this privacy policy.
What data do we collect?
We may collect the following information:
Your name, contact address, email address, telephone numbers (including mobile numbers)Your location
How do we use your data?
To authenticate you as a Supplier of the Company and contact you regarding legitimate commercial matters;
International Transfers
Sometimes it is necessary for us to share your data outside of the European Economic Area. This will typically happen if you are based, or are visiting, a country outside the EEA. If this happens, we will ensure that the transfer will be compliant with data protection law and all personal data will be secure.
How long will we keep your data for?
We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy. Different retention periods apply for different types of data, however the longest we will normally hold any personal data is 6 years.
How do we protect your data?
We are committed to keeping your personal data safe and secure. Our security measures include:
Encryption of electronic dataSecurity controls which protect our IT infrastructure from external attacks and unauthorised access. Internal policies limiting access to the dataInternal policies setting out our data security approach and training for employees
What are your rights?
You have the following rights:
the right to ask for a copy of personal data that we hold about you (the right of access);the right (in certain circumstances) to request we delete personal data held on you; where we no longer have any legal reason to retain it (the right of erasure);the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data that we hold about you (the right of rectification);the right to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you and to object to us using/holding your personal data if we have no legitimate reasons to do so (the right to object);the right (in certain circumstances) to ask us to ‘restrict processing of data’; which means we would need to secure and retain the data for your benefit but not otherwise use it (the right to restrict processing); andthe right (in certain circumstances) to ask us to supply you with some of the personal data we hold about you in a structured machine-readable format and/or to provide a copy of the data in such a format to another organisation (the right to data portability)
If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, you can email us at gdpr@hanovia.com or write to:
The Data Protection Officer, Hanovia Ltd, 780 Buckingham Avenue, Slough, SL1 4LA.
Legal Basis for processing personal data
We collect and use your personal data because it is necessary for:
the pursuit of our legitimate interests (as set out below); orcomplying with our legal obligations
Our legitimate interests
The normal legal basis for processing your data, is that it is
necessary for the legitimate interests of the Company, including: –
protecting customers, suppliers, employees and other individuals and maintaining their safety, health and welfarecomplying with our legal and regulatory obligationshandling customer and supplier contacts, queries, complaints or disputes
Updating our privacy policy
We will update this privacy policy as required, indicating the date of change. This policy was last updated on July 23rd, 2018.
back to top
Subsidiary Privacy Statement
Our name/contact details are Hanovia Ltd, 780 Buckingham Avenue, Slough, SL1 4LA
Please contact us on 01753 515300 or email gdpr@hanovia.com if you have any questions relating to this privacy policy.
What data do we collect?
We may collect the following information:
Your name, contact address, email address, telephone numbers (including mobile numbers)Your location
How do we use your data?
To authenticate you as an authorised user of the Company’s or Group’s systemsTo identify which systems you should have access to
International Transfers
Sometimes it is necessary for us to share your data outside of the European Economic Area. This will typically happen if you are based, or are visiting, a country outside the EEA. If this happens, we will ensure that the transfer will be compliant with data protection law and all personal data will be secure.
How long will we keep your data for?
We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy. Different retention periods apply for different types of data, however the longest we will normally hold any personal data is 6 years.
How do we protect your data?
We are committed to keeping your personal data safe and secure. Our security measures include:
Encryption of electronic dataSecurity controls which protect our IT infrastructure from external attacks and unauthorised access.Internal policies limiting access to the dataInternal policies setting out our data security approach and training for employees.
What are your rights?
You have the following rights:
the right to ask for a copy of personal data that we hold about you (the right of access);the right (in certain circumstances) to request we delete personal data held on you; where we no longer have any legal reason to retain it (the right of erasure);the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data that we hold about you (the right of rectification);the right to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you and to object to us using/holding your personal data if we have no legitimate reasons to do so (the right to object);the right (in certain circumstances) to ask us to ‘restrict processing of data’; which means we would need to secure and retain the data for your benefit but not otherwise use it (the right to restrict processing); andthe right (in certain circumstances) to ask us to supply you with some of the personal data we hold about you in a structured machine-readable format and/or to provide a copy of the data in such a format to another organisation (the right to data portability)
If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, you can email us at gdpr@hanovia.com or write to: The Data Protection Officer, Hanovia Ltd, 780 Buckingham Avenue, Slough, SL1 4LA.
Legal Basis for processing personal data
We collect and use your personal data because it is necessary for:
the pursuit of our legitimate interests (as set out below);orcomplying with our legal obligations
Our legitimate interests
The normal legal basis for processing your data, is that it is
necessary for the legitimate interests of the Company, including: –
protecting customers, suppliers, employees and other individuals and maintaining their safety, health and welfarecomplying with our legal and regulatory obligationshandling customer and supplier contacts, queries, complaints or disputes
Updating our privacy policy
We will update this privacy policy as required, indicating the date of change. This policy was last updated on July 23rd, 2018.
back to top
Employee Privacy Notice
Introduction
This privacy statement explains how the Company collects and
processes personal information, or personal data, relating to its
employees, workers and contractors to manage the working relationship.
This personal information may be held by the Company on paper or in
electronic format.
We are required under the GDPR to notify you of the information
contained in this privacy notice.
This privacy notice applies to all
current and former employees, workers and contractors. It is
non-contractual and does not form part of any employment contract,
casual worker agreement, consultancy agreement or any other contract for
services.
Who are we?
The Company is the data controller (contact details at the end of this notice). This means we decide how your personal data is processed and for what purposes
What information does the Company collect and from what sources?
Personal information is any information about an individual from
which that person can be directly or indirectly identified. It doesn’t
include anonymised data, i.e. where all identifying particulars have
been removed.
The Company collects, uses and processes a range of personal information about you.
It may include, but is not limited to:
your contact details, including your name, address, telephone number and personal e-mail addressyour emergency contact details/next of kin including contact names,
title, addresses, personal telephone numbers and personal email
addresses (which could include details of your relationship to them and
your marital status or sexual orientation)your date of birthyour genderyour nationalityyour marital status and dependantsthe start and end dates of your employment or engagement*recruitment records, including personal information included in a CV,
any application form, cover letter, interview notes, references, copies
of proof of right to work in the UK documentation, passport, copies of
qualification certificates, copy of driving licence and other background
check documentationthe terms and conditions of your employment or engagement (including your job title and working hours), as set out in a job offer letter, employment contract, written statement of employment particulars, casual worker agreement, consultancy agreement, pay review and bonus letters, statements of changes to employment or engagement terms and related correspondencedetails of your skills, qualifications, experience and work history, both with previous employers and with the Companyyour professional membershipsyour salary, entitlement to benefits and pension informationyour National Insurance numberyour bank account details, payroll records, tax code and tax status informationany disciplinary, grievance and capability records, including investigation reports, collated evidence, minutes of hearings and appeal hearings, warning letters, performance improvement plans and related correspondenceappraisals, including appraisal forms, performance reviews and ratings, targets and objectives set (Talent management)training recordsannual leave and other leave records, including details of the types of and reasons for leave being taken and related correspondenceany termination of employment or engagement documentation, including resignation letters, dismissal letters, redundancy letters, minutes of meetings, settlement agreements and related correspondenceinformation obtained through electronic means, such as swipecard or clocking-in system recordsinformation about your use of our IT systems, including usage of telephones, e-mail and the Internet*photographs, typically used internally only for ID cards, company
announcements, organisation charts, first aid charts and the company
intranetyour social networking profiles and/or internet profiles whether professional or personalinformation about your performance including meetings (whether internally or with customers), appraisals, pay rises, promotions and complaints (whether made by you or about you)information about expense claims (which may include information about your location on a specific date)details of leave for family or personal reasons (e.g. maternity, paternity, shared parental or adoption leave)information for insurance purposes (including information about other people connected to you such as family members) whether that insurance is taken out by us for our own benefit or to provide a benefit to youdriving licence, car registration, car insurance detailsinformation on your membership of, or being a representative of, a trade unionhealth and safety incidentsmonitoring on diversity (including, for example, age, race/ethnicity,
religion, whether you have a disability, sexual orientation, gender
identity and marital status)communications with and information held by those responsible for managing you and others working with you: for example, timekeeping, ability, teamwork, attitude, work allocation, and attendance at work-related social eventsinformation about your health, including any medical condition,
whether you have a disability in respect of which the Company needs to
make reasonable adjustments, sickness absence records (including details
of the reasons for sickness absence being taken), medical reports and
related correspondence*ascertain your fitness to work
The information shown in bold is or could include “special categories”
of personal information. Under data protection laws, “special
categories” of personal information (previously known as sensitive
personal data) includes information revealing racial or ethnic origin,
political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union
membership, genetic information, biometric information for uniquely
identifying a person and information concerning a person’s health, sex
life or sexual orientation. Information concerning criminal convictions
is placed in a similar category. This information is particularly
sensitive and we will therefore only process this information where
absolutely necessary: we will ensure it is only seen by those who have
to see it; and will keep it secure. By law we are required to have a
policy document outlining how we protect such information and how long
the information is held for. Our policy document on this information
will be reviewed from time to time.
How do we collect your personal information?
The Company may collect personal information about employees, workers
and contractors in a variety of ways. It is collected during the
recruitment process, either directly from you or sometimes from a third
party such as an employment agency. We may also collect personal
information from other external third parties, such as references from
former employers, information from background check providers, and in
certain situations information from credit reference agencies.
We will also collect additional personal information throughout the
period of your working relationship with us. This may be collected in
the course of your work-related activities. Whilst some of the personal
information you provide to us is mandatory and/or is a statutory or
contractual requirement, some of it you may be asked to provide to us on
a voluntary basis. We will inform you whether you are required to
provide certain personal information to us or if you have a choice in
this.
Your personal information may be stored in different places,
including in your personnel file, in the Company’s HR management system
and in other IT systems, such as the e-mail system.
What is the legal basis for processing my personal data?
We will only use your personal information when the law allows us to. These are known as the legal bases for processing. We will use your personal information in one or more of the following circumstances:
where we need to do so to perform the employment contract, casual worker agreement, consultancy agreement or contract for services we have entered into with you where we need to comply with a legal obligationwhere it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party), and your interests or your fundamental rights and freedoms do not override our interests.We may also occasionally use your personal information where we need to protect your vital interests (or someone else’s vital interests).Where we have your explicit consent. Note that this only relates to use of the biometric hand scanner, (for timekeeping, overtime and wage processing)
How does the Company use my personal data?
The Company may use your data to:
enable us to maintain accurate and up-to-date employee, worker and contractor records and contact details (including details of whom to contact in the event of an emergency) run recruitment processes and assess suitability for employment, engagement or promotioncomply with statutory and/or regulatory requirements and obligations, e.g. checking your right to workcomply with the duty to make reasonable adjustments for disabled employees and workers and with other disability discrimination obligationsmaintain an accurate record of your employment or engagement termsadminister the contract we have entered into with youmake decisions about pay reviews and bonusesensure you are paid correctly and receive the correct benefits and pension entitlements, including liaising with any external benefits or pension providers or insurersensure compliance with income tax requirements, e.g. deducting income tax and National Insurance contributions where applicableoperate and maintain a record of disciplinary, grievance and capability procedures and action takenoperate and maintain a record of performance management systemsrecord and assess your education, training and development activities and needsplan for career development and successionenable effective workforce managementoperate and maintain a record of absence proceduresascertain your fitness to workoperate and maintain a record of maternity leave, paternity leave, adoption leave, shared parental leave, parental leave and any other type of paid or unpaid leave or time off workensure payment of SSP or contractual sick payensure payment of other statutory or contractual pay entitlements, e.g. SMP, SPP, SAP and ShPPmeet our obligations under health and safety lawsmake decisions about continued employment or engagementoperate and maintain a record of dismissal proceduresprovide references on request for current or former employees, workers or contractorsprevent fraudmonitor your use of our IT systems to ensure compliance with our IT-related policiesensure network and information security and prevent unauthorised access and modifications to systemsensure effective HR, personnel management and business administration, including accounting and auditingBusiness metrics, eg diversity, leavers, sickness absence etc.ensure adherence to Company rules, policies and proceduresmonitor equal opportunitiesenable us to establish, exercise or defend possible legal claims
What if you fail to provide personal information?
If you fail to provide certain personal information which we need in order to perform our contract with you, to protect our legitimate interests or to comply with a legal obligation, we may not be able to perform the contract we have entered into with you, or we may be prevented from complying with our legal obligations. You may also be unable to exercise your statutory or contractual rights
Change of purpose
We will only use your personal information for the purposes for which we collected it. If we need to use your personal information for a purpose other than that for which it was collected, we will provide you, prior to that further processing, with information about the new purpose, we will explain the legal basis which allows us to process your personal information for the new purpose and we will provide you with any relevant further information. We may also issue a new privacy notice to you.
Sharing my personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with the following:
with our Employees (line managers/leaders), agents and/or professional advisors;with other companies within the current and future HALMA Group, in respect of employees who are seconded, in respect of senior leadership team and for talent management purposes only; Where this happens, we have a data sharing agreement in place.with other approved third-party contractors who provide services to us, e.g. benefit providers, outsourced payroll processor; Occupational health provider, external IT providers, a detailed list is available from the GDPR owner.External Audit bodieswhere we are under a legal obligation to do so, for example where we are required to share information under statute, to prevent fraud and other criminal offences or because of a Court Order for example HRMC, the police.external auditorsprofessional advisers, such as lawyers and accountants
We may also need to share your personal information with a regulator or to otherwise comply with the law.
We may share your personal information with third parties where it is
necessary to administer the contract we have entered into with you,
where we need to comply with a legal obligation, or where it is
necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party).
How long do we keep your personal data?
The Company will only retain your personal information for as long as
is necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected and
processed, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, tax,
health and safety, reporting or accounting requirements.
The Company will generally hold your personal information for the duration of your employment or engagement.
Once you have left employment or your engagement has been terminated,
we will hold your personal information for 6 years after the
termination of your employment or engagement.
Personal information which is no longer to be retained will be
securely and effectively destroyed or permanently erased from our IT
systems and we will also require third parties to destroy or erase such
personal information where applicable.
In some circumstances we may
anonymise your personal information so that it no longer permits your
identification. In this case, we may retain such information for a
longer period.
Your biometric data is immediately and irretrievably deleted when your employment or engagement comes to an end.
Transferring my personal data outside the EEA
Sometimes it is necessary for us to share your data outside of the European Economic Area. This will typically happen if you are based, or are visiting, a country outside the EEA. If this happens, we will ensure that the transfer will be compliant with data protection law and all personal data will be secure.
Your rights in connection with your personal information
It is important that the personal information we hold about you is
accurate and up to date. Please keep us informed if your personal
information changes, e.g. you change your home address, during your
working relationship with the Company so that our records can be
updated. The Company cannot be held responsible for any errors in your
personal information in this regard unless you have notified the Company
of the relevant change.
As a data subject, you have a number of statutory rights. Subject to
certain conditions, and in certain circumstances, you have the right to:
request access to your personal information – this is usually known as making a data subject access request and it enables you to receive a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing itrequest rectification of your personal information – this enables you to have any inaccurate or incomplete personal information we hold about you correctedrequest the erasure of your personal information – this enables you to ask us to delete or remove your personal information where there’s no compelling reason for its continued processing, e.g. it’s no longer necessary in relation to the purpose for which it was originally collectedrestrict the processing of your personal information – this enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal information, e.g. if you contest its accuracy and so want us to verify its accuracyobject to the processing of your personal information – this enables you to ask us to stop processing your personal information where we are relying on the legitimate interests of the business as our legal basis for processing and there is something relating to your particular situation which makes you decide to object to processing on this grounddata portability – this gives you the right to request the transfer of your personal information to another party so that you can reuse it across different services for your own purposes.
If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact our GDPR owner. We may need to request specific information from you in order to verify your identity and check your right to access the personal information or to exercise any of your other rights. This is a security measure to ensure that your personal information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.
Withdrawal of consent
In the event that the company uses biometric data to monitor attendance. If you have provided your consent to the processing of your biometric data for the purposes of the clocking in/out scanner (which is used to process any overtime payments owed), you have the right to withdraw your consent to this at any time. If wish you to withdraw your consent, you should contact our GDPR owner. If you withdraw your consent we will irretrievably delete from our systems any and all biometric data held; however, this will mean that we will be unable to process any overtime payments owed to you.
Changes to this privacy notice
The Company reserves the right to update or amend this privacy notice at any time, including where the Company intends to further process your personal information for a purpose other than that for which the personal information was collected or where we intend to process new types of personal information. We will issue you with a new privacy notice when we make significant updates or amendments. We may also notify you about the processing of your personal information in other ways.
Complaints
If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal
data, you can contact our GDPR Owner who will investigate the matter,
(contact details below). Alternatively, you can complete the GDPR
complaints form that can be obtained from the Senior Secretary.
If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are not
processing your personal data in accordance with the law you can
complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), www.ico.org.uk
Contact details
Hanovia Ltd, 780-781 Buckingham Avenue, Slough, SL1 4LA. If you have any
questions regarding this privacy statement please contact Companies
GDPR owner at gdpr@hanovia.com or 01753 515 300 or www.hanovia.com
back to top
Customer Privacy Statement
Our name/contact details are Hanovia Ltd, 780 Buckingham Avenue, Slough SL1 4LA
Please contact us on 01753 515300 or email gdpr@hanovia.com if you have any questions relating to this privacy policy
What data do we collect?
We may collect the following information:
Your name, contact address, email address, telephone numbers (including mobile numbers)Your location
How do we use your data?
To authenticate you as a Customer of the Company and contact you regarding legitimate commercial matters;
International Transfers
Sometimes it is necessary for us to share your data outside of the European Economic Area. This will typically happen if you are based, or are visiting, a country outside the EEA. If this happens, we will ensure that the transfer will be compliant with data protection law and all personal data will be secure.
How long will we keep your data for?
We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy. Different retention periods apply for different types of data, however the longest we will normally hold any personal data is 6 years.
How do we protect your data?
We are committed to keeping your personal data safe and secure. Our security measures include:
Encryption of electronic dataSecurity controls which protect our IT infrastructure from external attacks and unauthorised access.Internal policies limiting access to the dataInternal policies setting out our data security approach and training for employees.
What are your rights?
You have the following rights:
the right to ask for a copy of personal data that we hold about you (the right of access);the right (in certain circumstances) to request we delete personal data held on you; where we no longer have any legal reason to retain it (the right of erasure);the right to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data that we hold about you (the right of rectification);the right to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you and to object to us using/holding your personal data if we have no legitimate reasons to do so (the right to object);the right (in certain circumstances) to ask us to ‘restrict processing of data’; which means we would need to secure and retain the data for your benefit but not otherwise use it (the right to restrict processing); andthe right (in certain circumstances) to ask us to supply you with some of the personal data we hold about you in a structured machine-readable format and/or to provide a copy of the data in such a format to another organisation (the right to data portability)
If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, you can email us at gdpr@hanovia.com or write to: The Data Protection Officer, Hanovia Ltd, 780 Buckingham Avenue, Slough, SL1 4LA.
Legal Basis for processing personal data
We collect and use your personal data because it is necessary for:
the pursuit of our legitimate interests (as set out below); orcomplying with our legal obligations
Our legitimate interests
The normal legal basis for processing your data, is that it is necessary for the legitimate interests of the Company, including: –
protecting customers, suppliers, employees and other individuals and maintaining their safety, health and welfarecomplying with our legal and regulatory obligationshandling customer and supplier contacts, queries, complaints or disputes
Updating our privacy policy
We will update this privacy policy as required, indicating the date of change. This policy was last updated on July 23rd, 2018.
back to top
Recruitment Privacy Notice
Introduction
As part of any recruitment process, we collect and processes personal
information, or personal data, relating to job applicants. This
personal information may be held by us on paper or in electronic format.
The Company is committed to being transparent about how it handles
your personal information, to protecting the privacy and security of
your personal information and to meeting its data protection obligations
under the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and the Data
Protection Act 2018. The purpose of this privacy notice is to make you
aware of how and why we will collect and use your personal information
during the recruitment process. We are required under the GDPR to notify
you of the information contained in this privacy notice.
This privacy notice applies to all job applicants, whether they apply
for a role directly or indirectly through an employment agency. It is
non-contractual.
Who are we?
The Company is the data controller (contact details at the end of this notice). This means we decide how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.
What are the Data Protection Principles?
Under the GDPR, there are six data protection principles that the Company must comply with. These provide that the personal information we hold about you must be:
Processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner.Collected only for legitimate purposes that have been clearly explained to you and not further processed in a way that is incompatible with those purposes.Adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to those purposes.Accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date.Kept in a form which permits your identification for no longer than is necessary for those purposes.Processed in a way that ensures appropriate security of the data.
The Company is responsible for, and must be able to demonstrate compliance with, these principles. This is called accountability
What types of personal information do we collect about you?
Personal information is any information about an individual from
which that person can be directly or indirectly identified. It doesn’t
include anonymised data, i.e. where all identifying particulars have
been removed.
The Company collects, uses and processes a range of personal
information about you during the recruitment process. This includes (as
applicable):
your contact details, including your name, address, telephone number and personal e-mail addresspersonal information included in a CV, any application form, cover letter or interview notesreferencesdate of birthconfirmation of your right to work in the UK and any conditions on it OR your identity documents to comply with right to work checks required by lawdetails of your skills, qualifications, experience and work history with previous employersinformation about your current salary level, including benefits and pension entitlementsyour professional membershipslogin and password details related to online application processcontact details of current and/or former employerscurrent work contact details including telephone numbers, and email addresseseducation records, training records and records of qualifications and achievementssocial networking profiles and/or internet profiles whether professional or personaljob title and job duties with current and/or former employersdetails of salary and reward package and notice period with current and/or former employersreason for leaving previous employment(s)whether previously applied for a position or worked for us or any of our group organisations before, or whether you are related to anyone who works for usthe contact details, occupation and position of refereesinformation gathered from reference requests – this could include information about absence; any disciplinary investigations and proceedings, whether or not any disciplinary action was taken; details of any grievance investigations or complaints raised by you, or by a third party about you, whether or not any action was taken; your performance, attitude and personalitypayroll, tax and national insurance informationhobbies, interests outside work and achievementsinformation on any disability and/or reasonable adjustments that would be required to enable you to attend an interviewmonitoring on diversity (including, for example, age, race/ethnicity, religion, whether you have a disability, sexual orientation, gender identity and marital status)your photographdetails of your driving licence;psychometric testingdigital data on your activity on business-related social networking sites and information about you from media articles in the public domain
How do we collect your personal information?
The Company collects personal information about you during the
recruitment process either directly from you or sometimes from a third
party such as an employment agency or sometimes from internet searches
(e.g. LinkedIn, Facebook, twitter etc). We may also collect personal
information from other external third parties, such as references from
current and former employers and information from background check
providers. Other than employment agencies, we will only seek personal
information from third parties during the recruitment process once an
offer of employment has been made to you and we will inform you that we
are doing so.
You are under no statutory or contractual obligation to provide
personal information to the Company during the recruitment process.
Your personal information may be stored in different places,
including on your application record, in our HR management system and in
other IT systems, such as the e-mail system
Why, and how do we use your personal information and what is the legal basis for processing my personal data?
We will only use your personal information when the law allows us to. These are known as the legal bases for processing. We will use your personal information in one or more of the following circumstances:
where we need to comply with a legal obligationwhere it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party), and your interests or your fundamental rights and freedoms do not override our interests. (Our legitimate interests include: pursuing our business by employing employees, workers and contractors; managing the recruitment process; conducting due diligence on prospective staff and performing effective internal administration).
The purposes for which we are processing, or will process, your personal information are to:
manage the recruitment process and assess your suitability for employment or engagementdecide to whom to offer a jobensure compliance with your statutory rightsensure effective HR, personnel management and business administrationmonitor equal opportunitiesenable us to establish, exercise or defend possible legal claims
What if you fail to provide personal information?
If you fail to provide certain personal information when requested, we may not be able to process your job application properly or at all, we may not be able to enter into a contract with you, or we may be prevented from complying with our legal obligations. You may also be unable to exercise your statutory rights.
Change of purpose
We will use your personal information for the purposes for which we collected it, i.e. for the recruitment exercise for which you have applied, however if your application for employment or engagement is successful, the personal information gathered during the recruitment process will be retained for the duration of your employment or engagement and in accordance with the privacy notice for employees, workers and contractors.
Who has access to your personal information?
Your personal information may be shared internally within the Company
for the purposes of the recruitment exercise, including with members of
the HR department, members of the recruitment team and managers in the
department which has the vacancy.
We will not share your personal information with third parties during
the recruitment process unless your job application is successful, and
we make you an offer of employment or engagement. At that stage, we may
also share your personal information with third parties (and their
designated agents), including:
external organisations for the purposes of conducting pre-employment reference and employment background checkscurrent or former employers, to obtain referencesprofessional advisors, such as lawyersOccupational health for the purpose of employment health questionnaires.
We may also need to share your personal information with a regulator or to otherwise comply with the law.
How does the Company protect your personal information?
We have put in place measures to protect the security of your
personal information. It has internal policies, procedures and controls
in place to try and prevent your personal information from being
accidentally lost or destroyed, altered, disclosed or used or accessed
in an unauthorised way. In addition, we limit access to your personal
information to those employees, workers, agents, contractors and other
third parties who have a business need to know in order to perform their
job duties and responsibilities.
Where your personal information is shared with third parties, we
require all third parties to take appropriate technical and
organisational security measures to protect your personal information
and to treat it subject to a duty of confidentiality and in accordance
with data protection law. We only allow them to process your personal
information for specified purposes and in accordance with our written
instructions and we do not allow them to use your personal information
for their own purposes.
We also have in place procedures to deal with a suspected data
security breach and we will notify the Information Commissioner’s Office
and you of a suspected breach where we are legally required to do so.
How long do we keep your personal data?
We will only retain your personal information for as long as is
necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected and
processed.
If your application for employment or engagement is unsuccessful, we
will generally hold your personal information for one year after the end
of the relevant recruitment exercise
If your application for employment or engagement is successful,
personal information gathered during the recruitment process will be
retained for the duration of your employment or engagement and in
accordance with the privacy notice for employees, workers and
contractors.
Personal information which is no longer to be retained will be
securely and effectively destroyed or permanently erased from our IT
systems and we will also require third parties to destroy or erase such
personal information where applicable.
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal information so
that it no longer permits your identification. In this case, we may
retain such information for a longer period.
Transferring your personal data outside the EEA
Sometimes it is necessary for us to share your data outside of the European Economic Area. This will typically happen if you are based, or are visiting, a country outside the EEA. If this happens, we will ensure that the transfer will be compliant with data protection law and all personal data will be secure.
Your rights in connection with your personal information
As a data subject, you have a number of statutory rights. Subject to
certain conditions, and in certain circumstances, you have the right to:
request access to your personal information – this is usually known as making a data subject access request and it enables you to receive a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing itrequest rectification of your personal information – this enables you to have any inaccurate or incomplete personal information we hold about you correctedrequest the erasure of your personal information – this enables you to ask us to delete or remove your personal information where there’s no compelling reason for its continued processing, e.g. it’s no longer necessary in relation to the purpose for which it was originally collectedrestrict the processing of your personal information – this enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal information, e.g. if you contest its accuracy and so want us to verify its accuracyobject to the processing of your personal information – this enables you to ask us to stop processing your personal information where we are relying on the legitimate interests of the business as our legal basis for processing and there is something relating to your particular situation which makes you decide to object to processing on this grounddata portability – this gives you the right to request the transfer of your personal information to another party so that you can reuse it across different services for your own purposes.
If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact our GDPR owner (contact details below) or the HR Department. We may need to request specific information from you in order to verify your identity and check your right to access the personal information or to exercise any of your other rights. This is a security measure to ensure that your personal information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.
Changes to this privacy notice
The Company reserves the right to update or amend this privacy notice at any time. We will issue you with a new privacy notice when we make significant updates or amendments. We may also notify you about the processing of your personal information in other ways.
Complaints
If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal
data, you can contact our GDPR Owner who will investigate the matter
(contact details below). Alternatively, you can complete the GDPR
complaints form that can be obtained from the Senior Secretary (Julie.cole@hanovia.com)
If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are not
processing your personal data in accordance with the law you can
complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), www.ico.org.uk
Contact details
The Company has a GDPR owner, who is responsible for being our point of
contact for all GDPR related enquiries or questions.
If you have any
questions regarding this privacy statement please contact them at
gdpr@hanovia.com or 01753 515300 or 780-1 Buckingham Avenue, Slough, SL1 4LA.
© 2020 All images, text and content are copyright of We UV Care / Berson UV / Aquionics UV / Hanovia UV
|
We reserve the right to amend and change product & UV specifications without prior notice
